(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
準備中
Preparing
ゴザル ゴザル
Gozaru Gozaru
なんでもござれ ゴザット
Anything goes, Gozatto
斬り捨て御免の マジカル・ワード
Slaying with "sorry", Magical Word
I-M-B I-M-B
魔法の呪文 I-M-B
Magic spell, I-M-B
マジカル ゴザル レッツゴー
Magical Gozaru Let's Go
朝 目が覚めたら 遅刻寸前
When I woke up in the morning, I was almost late
お気に入りのわらじも 履いたなら
If I put on my favorite straw sandals
駆け抜けるアベニュー
I'll run through the avenue
脳内 シャキーン シャキーン
My brain goes "shakiin shakiin"
イッツ・マジカル バンッ!
It's Magical Bang!
どこから見ても 魔法少女なり
No matter how you look at it, I'm a magical girl
ひれ伏せ 皆様
Kneel down, everyone
至福 此処 安
Bliss is right here, peace
悪代官 奴等 退治は お安い 御用
Exterminating those corrupt officials is an easy task
拙者の腕の見せ所になるでござる
It's time for me to show my skills, degozaru
マジカル抜刀斬り！
Magical Draw-and-Slash!
ゴザル ゴザル 討ち入りでござる
Gozaru Gozaru, it's a raid degozaru
マジカルな峰打ちを お見舞いするでござる
I'll give you a magical strike with the back of my blade, degozaru
ゴザル ゴザル
Gozaru Gozaru
この世界を守る
Protecting this world
完璧に 華麗な 姿をご覧あれ
Behold my perfectly beautiful figure
魔法少女マジカルゴザル
Magical Girl Magical Gozaru
フリフリヒラヒラ そよ風に舞う
Fluttering and waving, dancing in the breeze
袴の裾を ちょっとつまんでキメポーズ
Pinching the hem of my hakama for a pose
崇めよ 皆様
Worship me, everyone
御座んなんの 麗しきお姫様
Here comes the beautiful princess
だけど言えない その正体
But I can't tell you my true identity
秘密こそ至上のテンプレでござる
A secret is the ultimate template, degozaru
ゴザル ゴザル
Gozaru Gozaru
闇討ちでござる
It's a surprise attack, degozaru
魔法少女は食わねど高揚枝でござる
A magical girl keeps a stiff upper lip even when hungry, degozaru
ゴザル ゴザル
Gozaru Gozaru
魔法の国から
From the kingdom of magic
お忍びで舞い降りた
Flew down in secret
謎の転校生
The mysterious transfer student
魔法少女マジカルゴザル
Magical Girl Magical Gozaru
こんばんは 風真いろはです。
Good evening, I'm Kazama Iroha.
今日は3周年 おいわい感謝！
Celebrating my 3rd anniversary today, thank you!
来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming!
最初に皆さんに少しだけお話をさせて下さい
Please let me talk to you for a bit first.
お察しのとおりですが
As you might have guessed,
今、声がでません。
I can't speak right now.
原因は端的に言うと
The reason, in short, is
ストレスからくる心因性失声症です。
psychogenic aphonia caused by stress.
お医者さんに診断いただきました。
I received this diagnosis from a doctor.
端的な説明すぎて誤解を招きたくないので
Since that explanation is so brief and I don't want it to be misunderstood,
はっきり言うと
to put it clearly,
クロエの卒業とは関係ないというか
it's not related to Chloe's graduation, or rather...
もちろんすごくさみしいです
Of course, I'm very sad about it.
正直今日の配信は前から不安でした。
To be honest, I've been anxious about today's stream for a while.
他のこともふくめ、心に負荷がかかりすぎた。
Including other things, it was too much of a burden on my heart.
それだけです。
That's all it is.
タイミングとかもある。
There's also the matter of timing.
でも全部仕方ない。
But it's all unavoidable.
だれも悪くない。
Nobody is at fault.
しいて言えば、これが弱かった。
If I had to say, this was weak.
←これです。
<- This is it.
明日、声がでるかもだし、ずっとでないかもだし、
My voice might come back tomorrow, or it might not for a long time,
わかりませんが、
I don't know, but...
今日は絶対、皆を１人にしたくなくて、
today, I absolutely didn't want to leave everyone alone,
わがまま言って配信してます。
so I'm being selfish and streaming.
ご心配をおかけして、本当にごめんなさい！
I'm really sorry for making you worry!
今日は楽しい気持ちを、
Today, I want to...
沢山皆さんと共有したい、共有したい！
...share many happy feelings with everyone!
本当に来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming.
今日はおひろめ盛り沢山あるので、
There are many unveilings today, so...
今日はお披露目あるので...
Since there's a reveal today...
...ゆっくり楽しんでいってね！
...please enjoy it at your own pace!
元気になっていってね！
I hope you feel energized!
ではしばし待て！
Now, please wait a moment!
お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
ひんとはこれね↑
Here's a hint↑
いくよ？
Ready?
でか
They're big...
はしれる？
Can I run in these?
靴下はくるぶし隠した＾＾
The socks cover the ankles ^^
はずいからくるぶし未だだ！
It's embarrassing, so no ankles yet!
いつも思うの
I always think...
いつも思うの...
ママ層...
Moms...
みじかいの...
...the short ones...
...スキだよね
...you love them, don't you?
みじかい！
It's short!
走れる??
Can you run in this??
ふあん
I'm worried
え！
Eh!
これもしや...
Could this be...
もえそで？
Moesode?
MOESODE
パーカー
Hoodie
よく着る
I wear it often
うれしいね
That makes me happy
みてこれ
Look at this
ぽこぺえ！
Pokopee!
ゆらゆら
Swaying
またいる
It's there again
セーラーだ！
It's a sailor uniform!
ファンアート
Fan art
羽のった
The wings are on
うれしかった
I was happy
さいごまで
Until the very end
いくわ～ん
Let's go!
ズドーン！！
BOOM!!
みっあみ
Braids
どうぞ！
Here you go!
みつあみどうよ！
How do you like the braids?
全身みる？
Want to see the whole thing?
天才！神！走れる！袖！
Genius! God-tier! Can run! Sleeves!
しかも、動くんじゃんアイツ。
And that guy actually moves.
脱げるヨ
You can take it off!
最近寒いから
Since it's been cold lately...
あったかいのあるよ～～
I have something warm here~~
ポコべえ
Poko-be!
あと、散髪。
Also, a haircut.
イケメン！
Looking cool!
どれが好きかハイク？
Which do you like? Haiku!
どれが好きか ハイコメ
Which do you like? High-speed comment
ぷりーず
please
やったー！
Yay!
じつは今日...
Actually today...
声でて 1人じゃないから
there are voices, I'm not alone.
ホロメンよんだ
I called some Hololive members.
よんでいい？
Can I call them out?
もうこちら触ってよろしいでしょうか？
May I touch this now?
やはりショートカットにかーわーいーあまりにも精錬されておるぜ！
As expected, a shortcut is so cute! It's too refined!
おさげ！ おさげ！
Braids! Braids!
おさげ派とショート派でちょっと分かれてて...
Braids and short hair camps are a bit divided...
あーそうなの？
Oh, really?
どっちがいいかって話を後ろでしてたんだけど。
We were talking in the back about which one is better.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
あ、もしかして我々の声まだ入ってないじゃないですか？
Oh, maybe our voices aren't being heard yet?
はいってるよ！
They're in!
あの、えっと、ラプラス殿はどっちなんですっけ？
Um, so, which one was it for you, Laplus-dono?
や、僕は完全におさげに決まってますね。
Well, for me, it's definitely braids.
おさげでカーディガンが推し?
Braids and a cardigan is your preference?
おさげでカーディガンです、完全に。
Braids and a cardigan, absolutely.
じゃあおさげカーディガン、はい、いろは。
Then braids and cardigan. Okay, Iroha...
これでおさげしろ！って髪伸ばせ！
Now do braids! Grow your hair!
OK
のばせ！ のばせ！ のばせ！
Grow it! Grow it! Grow it!
きたー！
It's here!
ぐわー！さすがにかわいい！
Gah! As expected, it's cute!
さすがにいい！
As expected, it's good!
やっぱカーディガンいいね。
A cardigan is nice after all.
自分もいいっすね、あ、言っちゃってくださいよ。
I like it too. Oh, go ahead and say it.
やっぱりあの、ショートヘアで全部脱いだ、全部脱いだっていうか...
After all, with short hair and having taken it all off... wait, I mean...
ちょっ、警察呼ぶから!
Wait, I'm calling the police!
!? ぬぐ？
!? Take off?
カーディガンとパーカーを取った...
Taking off the cardigan and hoodie...
うちのいろはちゃん、そういうのやってないんで。
Our Iroha-chan doesn't do that kind of thing.
すみません、すみません、言わないでくださいね。
Sorry, sorry. Don't say that.
じゃあちょっといろはちゃん、髪の毛を散髪して、カーデを脱いでいただいて...
Then Iroha-chan, cut your hair and take off the cardigan for a bit...
寒いけど... ごめんね。
It's cold but... sorry.
OK! あ、もうそうです、下半袖だわ。
OK! Ah, that's right. It's short-sleeved underneath.
寒い寒い... いろはちゃん寒いじゃない。
It's cold, it's cold... isn't Iroha-chan cold?
ばー！ おー！ これ！
Baa! Oh! This!
この清楚、やばい！
This purity is amazing!
清楚のデザインがいいっすね。うちのホロライブに足りてないものかも、いまこれ。
The design of the purity is good. This might be what Hololive is lacking right now.
あ、そうだね、この光の感じがやばいです。
Ah, right. This feeling of light is incredible.
光属性いなくなっていってる気がするもん。
I feel like the 'light attribute' is disappearing.
そんなこと言わないで...
Don't say that...
みんなね、なんかコソコソとさ、来てるじゃん。
Everyone is, you know, coming in secretively.
そう、そこにこのいろはのこの制服ですよ。
Yeah, and then there's this uniform of Iroha's.
もうね、あのね、この何もないこのさっぱり感が逆にいい。
You know, this simple, clean feeling is actually better.
わかるわかる、いい、いい。
I get it, I get it. It's good, it's good.
珍しい、珍しくない？
It's rare, isn't it?
だってみんな結構さ、ゴテコテ、ギラギラって感じだけど。
Because everyone usually goes for flashy stuff.
そう、もう何でも全部つける！
Yeah, they just put everything on!
ただの制服って。
Just a uniform.
でもでも、いろは氏、やっぱこれを脱いだら下普通に...
But but, Iroha-shi, if you take this off,
ワンピースみたいなのもちょっと...
the one-piece-like dress underneath...
アルティメットになった...
It became ultimate...
ぬぐ、もう脱いじゃったんだけど...
Take off? I already took it off...
すぐ脱がせようとするの、やめてもらってよろしいか？
Can you stop trying to make her strip immediately?
ない、ないんだよ、普通にこれだとゆるゆる形式の服だし。
No, there isn't. Normally this is a loose-fitting style of clothing.
あ、ワンピースタイプね、ワンピースタイプ。
Ah, one-piece type, one-piece type.
うーん、なんかワンピースタイプの服になる、みたいなことはないの？
Hmm, is there no way for it to become a one-piece style outfit?
これ、この上のTシャツのところを、上にグッとバッとやったら...
If you pull up this T-shirt part here,
どうなるんすか？
what happens?
いや、だから...
No, like I said...
ない...ですが パーカー
None... but a hoodie
短くなってんのよ、下が。
The bottom part is short.
え、本当だ。
Oh, you're right.
だってこんなに短い。短かったらもうダメでしょ。おへそ見えちゃうでしょ。
Look how short it is. If it's this short, it's no good. Your belly button will show.
パーカーぶかぶか
Baggy hoodie
いや、だからそのね、この上はどうなってんの。
Well, then, what's going on with the top?
気になる、気になる。
I'm curious, I'm curious.
ちょっと脱げたら...
If you could just take it off...
お母さんに言え！
Tell it to your mom!
え、ちょっと見せてくれてるんですけど。
Oh, she's actually showing us a little.
みえるかぃ？
Can you see it?!
ちょっと、ちょっと見せないであげて。
Wait, don't show it.
あ、やばいやばい。これどうなってんの。
Oh, dangerous. How is this structured?
だから下がワンピース、な、あの、あれなんだって。
I told you, the bottom is a one-piece, uh, that kind of thing.
もう分かんない、もう！ゆるゆりを見ろお前は、だから！
I don't get it anymore! Just watch YuruYuri, you!
お前知識が足りんのや。
You lack knowledge.
ゆるゆりを見ろな。
Watch YuruYuri.
女の子のこと分かんないよ。
I don't understand girls.
お、ゆるゆりで分かるから、女の子のこと。
Oh, you can learn about girls from YuruYuri.
そうなの？
Is that so?
そうだよ。
Yes, it is.
なんかツヤツヤだね。
It's kind of shiny.
ワイ、ローファーもね、良かったよ、すごく。
I think the loafers were very good too.
なんかポルカさん、あの、いろはさんの足について語ってましたよね。
Polka-san, you were talking about Iroha's legs, weren't you?
足ですか？あの、とてもシンプルながら、すごく良い足をしていて。
Legs? Well, while they're simple, they're very good legs.
そうですね。なんかね、ちょっとスタンダードなお御足って感じで。
Right. They feel like standard beautiful legs.
はい。足。分かります。
Yes. Legs. I get it.
あし！
Legs!
このね、装飾とかない感じが良いんですよね。
The lack of decorations is what's good about them.
それです！
That's it!
もうシンプル足っていう。
Just 'simple legs'.
そう、我が輩はそれが、我が、あ、言っちゃった、我が言っちゃった。
Right, I thought that... I, oh, I said it, I said 'wagahai'.
我が輩は良いと思うよ。
I think they're good.
いや本当にめでたい、3周年。
Really, congratulations on the 3rd anniversary.
いや、素敵な衣装ですね。
It's a wonderful outfit.
え、あ、そういえば、君は制服派？
Oh, by the way, are you a school uniform person?
うれしい ありがたい
Happy and grateful
ねーよ、ねーよ、ねーよ。
No, no, no.
っていうことはやはり、こより氏との匂わせなのかもしれない。
So, as I thought, it might be a hint of something with Koyori-shi.
あ、やめてください。
Ah, please stop.
なんでカーディガンを選んだんだね？いろはちゃん。
Why did you choose a cardigan, Iroha-chan?
えっ なんで
Eh, why?
いろはちゃん、なんでカーディガンにしたの？
Iroha-chan, why did you go with a cardigan?
パーカーもあるよね、いろはちゃん。
There's also a hoodie option, right, Iroha-chan?
なんでだろうね？
I wonder why?
ねえ、なんでだろ、この、こよりさんとのこの匂わせみたいなことしちゃって。
Hey, I wonder why? Doing this sort of hint-giving thing with Koyori-san.
なんだか、こよりさんと並んだらすごくバランスが良さそうだよね。
It seems like the balance would be really good if you stood next to Koyori-san.
うっ殿 ごめんね^^
Ugh, Dono, sorry^^
あ、もう強制的に制服衣装を作らなければいけないような、この圧を感じるのですが。
I feel this pressure, like we're being forced to make school uniform outfits now.
いやいや、ルイ・ルイも作らなきゃいけないから。
No, no, Lui-Lui has to make one too.
あ、まあ確かにルイもそうですね。
Ah, well, true, Lui too.
みんな、みんな、ルイはさ、あの私服衣装がさ、あれ、先生みたい。
Everyone, everyone... Lui... her plain clothes outfit looks like a teacher's.
先生っぽい、先生っぽい！先生っぽいから、ちゃん。
Like a teacher, like a teacher! Because she looks like a teacher.
え、じゃあな。
Well then.
ごめんね。
Sorry.
あ、いろは氏、プレゼント送ったんですけど、これ着られます？
Oh, Iroha-shi, I sent you a present. Can you wear this?
もう、いろはさん煽るのやめてもらってよろしいか。
Could you please stop teasing Iroha-san?
ごめんね。
Sorry.
ｗｗ
lol
まじで煽るのやめてもらっていいか。
Can you seriously stop teasing me?
わらわら。コメント読んで、わらわら。
Haha. Reading the comments, haha.
ごめんね、わらわら。あ、いろはさん、そうだよ、プレゼント見たいっすね。
Sorry, haha. Oh, Iroha-san, right, I'd like to see the present.
ちょっと、これ行けます？
Wait, can we do this?
きたん
It's here
これ行けます？かけていただきたい、どうっすか。
Can we do this? I'd like you to put them on. How is it?
お願いします、お願いします。準備していいから全然。俺ら喋ってるからさ。
Please, please. Take your time to prepare. We'll keep talking.
あ、そうそう、こっち喋る全然。
Ah, right, we'll talk.
汚いこと喋る、全然。
We'll talk about dirty things, definitely.
汚いことダメだ。おめでたいこと喋る。
Dirty things are a no-go. We'll talk about celebratory things.
汚いことやめてくださいよ。3周年ですよ、いろはさんの。
Please stop with the dirty talk. It's Iroha's 3rd anniversary.
3周年！先輩、3周年！
3rd anniversary! Senpai, 3rd anniversary!
いや、まさかさ、色々お披露目って言ってさ、こんなに大々的にお洋服...
I mean, really, you said there'd be various reveals, but such big reveals for clothes...
きたー！
It's here!
ちょ、おまっ、いやいいっす、やっぱりマジカルござるの時のメガネ。これ似合います。
Wait, you... No, it's good. After all, it's the glasses from 'Magical Gozaru'. They suit you.
やはりこの形、あ、ちょっと待って。そしたらラプラス、もしかしてお下げにしないといけないのではないか。
Indeed, this shape... Oh, wait. In that case, La+, shouldn't we put her hair in pigtails?
あ、確かにお下げがいいじゃないですか。やはりこれはマジカルござるの再現をした方がよろしいかと。
Ah, definitely, pigtails would be good. I think it would be better to reproduce 'Magical Gozaru'.
つまりじゃあ、お下げにしたほうがいいという、そうですね。
So then, it's better to go with pigtails, right?
普通にお下げにしてもらって。そんな無理難題じゃないでござるよ。普通にお下げ。お下げにしよう。
Just have them put in pigtails. It's not such a difficult request. Just normal pigtails. Let's do pigtails.
お願いします。
Please.
はよ、はよ、お下げ、あ、きたー！
Hurry, hurry, pigtails... Oh, it's here!
いやー、これいい。ポルカさん、いいメガネ買ってきましたね。
Wow, this is great. Polka-san, you bought some good glasses.
我が一生に一片の悔いなし！それでは！
I have no regrets in my life! Well then!
あいつ消えた。ポルカー！
He disappeared. Polka!
消えました。
She disappeared.
じゃあいろはちゃん。頑張ったな。チュッチュッチュッ。
Well then, Iroha-chan. You did your best. Chu chu chu.
うれしいね！
I'm happy!
あ、もしもし。いろは先輩、入っちゃって大丈夫でしょうか。
Ah, hello. Iroha-senpai, is it okay if I come in?
うわ、きたー！
Whoa, it's here!
こんにちは こがねいさん
Hello, Koganei-san
あ、す、あ、すいません。緊張してるんですけど、あの。
Ah, s-, sorry. I'm nervous, but...
こんにちは。あ、こんにち...あ、ちょっと自己紹介と、FlowGlowのこがねいニコと申します。
Hello. Ah, hell... Ah, a quick self-introduction. I'm Niko Koganei from FlowGlow.
こっちもです！ こんにちは！
Same here! Hello!
いろは先輩、3周年、おめでとうございます！
Iroha-senpai, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
こっちもです！こんにちは！
Me too! Hello!
いや 直接お祝いできてめちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。
Wow, I'm so happy I could celebrate with you directly.
いやいやいやいや、嬉しいでござる、嬉しいでござる。
No no no no, I'm happy-degozaru, I'm happy-degozaru.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
めっちゃ緊張した。
I was so nervous.
あー、ちょっとですね...
Ah, wait a second...
...やばかったですね、いろは先輩の...
...that was crazy, Iroha-senpai's...
...この清楚、敵いません。
...neatness is unbeatable.
敵いません、ちょっと。
I can't compete, really.
W SEISO...
超清楚です。
It's super 'seiso'.
あ、何かすみません。
Ah, sorry about that.
後ろに、後ろに、後ろに寸断してる。
Behind... behind... it's cut off behind us.
どうしよう、どうしよう。
What should I do, what should I do?
わー！うれし！
Wow! Happy!
後ろに、あ、何で動かないの？
Behind... ah, why isn't it moving?
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Wait a second, wait a second.
何か固まってる。何で？ごめんなさい。
It's frozen. Why? I'm sorry.
動かない。いろは先輩、すみません。
It won't move. Iroha-senpai, I'm sorry.
大丈夫ですよ。
It's okay.
だいじょうぶ
It's okay
大丈夫ですか？静止画でも。
Are you okay? Even if it's a still image.
すみません。こちらだと動いてるんですけど。
Sorry. It's moving on my end.
いや、ちょっとね、やっぱりいろは先輩みたいに...
Well, you know, just like Iroha-senpai...
...清楚でかっこいい金髪美少女になれるように...
...I want to become a neat and cool blonde beauty...
...ちょっとにこも頑張りたいと思います。
...so Niko will work hard too.
え！かっこいい...
Eh! So cool...
え、敵いませんよ、いろは先輩には。
Eh, I can't compete with Iroha-senpai.
かっこよさも。
Even in coolness.
いや、もちろん、あのにこはですね...
Well, of course, Niko is...
...いろは先輩の鞘ですので。
...Iroha-senpai's scabbard.
はい。ちょっとこちらを今回...
Yes. I'd like to...
...お送りさせていただきたいと思います。
...send this to you this time.
さや！！
Saya!!
こちらいろは先輩、いろは先輩のさや剣でございます。
This is Iroha-senpai's scabbard sword.
きた！
It's here!
あー！こちらぜひ、いつでも呼んでいただけたら鞘になりますので。
Ah! Please call me anytime and I'll be your scabbard.
いろは先輩のさや🍎です
I'm Iroha-senpai's scabbard
やばい、出されると恥ずかしい。
Oh man, it's embarrassing when it's shown.
ぜひぜひ、あの今後ともよろしくお願いします、いろは先輩。
Please, I look forward to working with you from now on as well, Iroha-senpai.
あの、最後におねだりがあるんですけど。
Um, I have one last request...
え、ぜひお願いします。
Eh, please, go ahead.
一緒にござる合戦しましょう。
Let's have a 'gozaru' battle together.
声でたらあそんで下さい
Please play with me if I find my voice
あの、最後にお願いがあるんですけど、いろは先輩。
Um, I have one last request, Iroha-senpai.
にこたんって、あの文字でいいので、呼んでいただけないかなと思って。
I was wondering if you could call me 'Nikotan', even just in writing.
こがねいさんもいいんですけど、こがねいさんもいいんですけど...
'Koganei-san' is fine too, but...
...にこたんって呼んでいただけたらもう発狂して出ていきます。
...if you call me 'Nikotan', I'll go crazy and leave.
うん！
Yeah!
にこたん♡
Nikotan♡
うわー！いろは先輩！あー！大好きです！
Whoa! Iroha-senpai! Ah! I love you!
ありがとうございました！皆様失礼いたします！
Thank you very much! Everyone, excuse me!
にこたん♡ありがとう！！さや
Nikotan♡ Thank you!! Saya
みんなやさしい
Everyone is kind
おー！よいよいよいよいよいよい。
Oh! Good good good...
なんか、あれだね。やっぱりさ、動かないね。
Somehow, it's like... as I thought, it's not moving.
こうやってさ、動いてはいるけどさ。
Even though it's moving like this...
ござるはさ、固まってんだよね。
Gozaru-san is frozen.
これはこっちの問題なのかな？
Is this a problem on my end?
どうなんだろうね、ござるさん。
I wonder... Gozaru-san?
ちょっと待って、あはははは。
Wait a minute, hahahaha.
わかる。こっちないw
I get it. Not on my end lol
おまち！
Wait!
おまち！ござる多分ね...
Wait! Gozaru-san, you're probably...
...最新じゃないでござるよ。
...not updated.
そ、それじゃなかろうか。
Maybe that's it.
あ。
Ah.
つっ...
Ugh...
うう。いろいろ過去に取り残されてんだな、ござるは。
Ugh. I guess I'm left behind in the past.
うう、ござるが消えてしまったな。
Ugh, I've disappeared.
画面にはずっと、わけわかんない鞘があるだけだ。
There's just a mysterious scabbard left on the screen.
この鞘大丈夫かい。お蔵入りかな。
Is this scabbard okay? Will this be archived?
Y どうでしょ！おしりなの...？さや
Y How is it! Is it a butt...? Saya
ガチか。お尻なのか。
Seriously? Is it a butt?
お尻なの...？どうだろ、お尻いけるかな？
Is it a butt...? I wonder if a butt is okay.
あれ。画面にござるがいない。
Huh. I'm not on the screen.
画面、大丈夫かい。画面にござるがいない。
Is the screen okay? I'm not on the screen.
ちがうひと きたｗｗｗｗ
Someone else came lol
みんなに みせれんｗｗｗ
I can't show it to everyone lol
あ、来た。みんなに見せられんｗｗｗ
Ah, she's here. I can't show it to everyone lol
ふふふっ
Hehe
あ！なんじゃ、なんじゃ、なんじゃ、なんじゃ
Ah! What is it, what is it, what is it, what is it?
なんじゃこれ、なんじゃこれは
What is this, what is this?
ぜぷらぼ始まってる。あ、ある意味、ある意味そうだね。
Zaplab has started. Ah, in a sense, in a sense that's right.
ぜぷらぼ様とも提携してる。
Collaborating with Zaplab-sama too.
あ、来た来た来た。イエーイ、ゴダルー！
Ah, here it is, here it is. Yay, Godaru!
さあ、ゴダル、今ちょっと上半身アップめに映してショートになっていないかい？
Now, Godaru, aren't you showing just your upper body and looking like a shorty?
ほう、上半身アップめで、ショートになっとる時にちょっと気づいてしまったことがあるんだよね。
Ho, when it's zoomed in on the upper body and you look like a shorty, I've noticed something.
上半身アップでショートになっとる時に...
When it's zoomed in on the upper body and you're a shorty...
これさ、なんか僕たちショタみ感じない？
Don't we kind of feel like shotas here?
あはは。僕たちすごくショタみを感じないかい？
Ahahaha. Don't we feel very shota-like?
僕は常々そう思ってるよ。
I always think so.
ござる、声が出るようになったらショタコラボしないかい？
Gozaru, when your voice is back, shall we do a shota collab?
ホロライブのお姉ちゃんたちをまとおう。
Let's surround ourselves with Hololive's older sisters.
僕、なかなかホロライブにショタがいないから...
Since there aren't many shotas in Hololive...
いろはくん、いろはくんがショタみであって...
Iroha-kun, Iroha-kun having a shota vibe...
僕ショタみを感じるから...
Since I feel a shota vibe...
この僕とじゃあ一緒に声が出たらショタ配信をしよう。
Let's do a shota stream together once your voice is back.
僕、お姉さんすき！
I like older sisters!
わかる、僕もお姉さん好きで、ホロライブのお姉さんいい人ばっかだからね。
I get it, I like older sisters too, and the Hololive older sisters are all such good people.
じゃあいろはくん、じゃあ声出るようになったらじゃあ僕と一緒にショタ配信で...
Then Iroha-kun, once your voice is back, let's do a shota stream together...
ホロライブのお姉ちゃんたちをいっぱいっぱい呼びまくろう。
And call lots and lots of Hololive's older sisters.
やるます。
I'll do it.
やったー！ござる、3周年おめでとう。じゃあねー！
Yay! Gozaru, happy 3rd anniversary. See ya!
うれしい
I'm happy
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much
フブキ先輩
Fubuki-senpai
いろはおめでとー！
Iroha, congrats!
あははは！いろは、3周年おめでとー！
Ahahaha! Iroha, happy 3rd anniversary!
キャンプは1泊！？2泊！？無言ですまん！！
Camping for 1 night!? 2 nights!? Sorry for the silence!!
ドーナツ美味い！！！また遊ぼう！！！
Donuts are delicious!!! Let's play again!!!
おもろいｗｗ
Hilarious lol
スバル先輩
Subaru-senpai
ありがとうございますTT
Thank you very much TT
笑いすぎたんｗ
Laughed too much lol
他にもたくさん
There's a lot more
他にもたくさん写真もらいました！
I also received many other photos!
みなさん本当に
To everyone, I really...
ありがとうございます！
...thank you very much!
じゃあ告知していいかな？
So, is it okay if I make an announcement?
というわけで
And so...
告知です！
...here is the announcement!
まずはこれ！
First is this!
活動3周年記念フルセット
3rd Anniversary Memorial Full Set
1つめ
The first one...
高画質〜
...is high quality~
リバーシブルです！
It's reversible!
その2！
Number two!
ぽこべぇアイマスク！
The Pokobe eye mask!
フェスイベントとかでも使える！
You can use it at Fes events and such!
そい２、３！
One, two, three!
でかい
Huge!
↑ 25cm
すえ、すえる。
It can sit, it sits.
ぽこすい。
Pokosui.
おすすめ。
Recommended.
おむかえして...
Please adopt it...
おねがい！
Please!
そして！
And!
今までの衣装の
Of previous outfits,
アクキー♡
Acrylic key holders ♡
New
ｗｗｗ aipaddo sinda!
LOL the iPad died!
これでやるが
I'll use this but...
フルセット！
Full set!
かわいいネ＾＾
Isn't it cute? ^^
今回も直筆あり！
Hand-signed items included this time too!
21時カートOPEN!
Cart opens at 21:00!
ボイスは...
The voice pack is...
...ボイスは、は...。^ ^
...the voice is, well... ^ ^
魂削ってます。
I'm putting my soul into it.
よろしくお願いします
Please look forward to it.
そしてもう一ーつ
And one more thing...
告知があります！！
I have an announcement!!
新しいオリ曲です！
It's a new original song!
この曲の説明はこの後の
The explanation for this song will be...
ミニライブでしています
...given during the mini-live afterwards.
よかったら最後までみてって下さい！
Please watch until the end if you'd like!
MVは配信終了後に
The MV will be released after the stream ends...
リダイレクトでとばされるはず
...via a redirect.
なんと...恋愛ソングです
It's actually... a love song!
すご！ｗ
Wow! lol
リリースは12/1 24じです！
The release is on Dec. 1st at midnight!
げんていうりきれたま...？
Is the limited edition sold out...?
たくさん用意したんだがいつも瞬殺
I prepared a lot, but they always sell out instantly.
ほんとうにすまん。いつもありがとうございます
I'm really sorry. Thank you as always.
では、今日の最後 3Dライブ
Now for the finale, the 3D live.
こちらは誕生日のときに事前収録しました。
This was pre-recorded during my birthday.
今回のためにいろいろ誕生日でつかえる
For this occasion, I adjusted various
リソース調整してつくりました！
resources usable for birthdays!
こちらは誕生日のときに事前収録しました。
This was pre-recorded during my birthday.
今回のためにいろいろ誕生日でつかえるリソース調整してつくりました！
I adjusted various birthday resources to make this happen!
かざまの声します。
This is Kazama's voice.
今日初めてのかざまの声だね。
This is the first time you're hearing my voice today.
少しでも元気に、
I hope this makes you feel...
なっていってくれたら...
...even a little bit better.
それではさっそく、
So without further ado,
ミニライブGo!
Let's go to the mini-live!
そのあとはMV公開！
After that, the MV will be released!
さいごまで楽しんでいってね！！
Please enjoy until the very end!!
まちがえた ^ ^
I made a mistake ^ ^
こんどこそ！
This time for sure!
風がそっと吹いたら
If the wind blows gently,
始まる合図でござる！
it's the signal to start, degozaru!
いろはすてっぷ！
Iroha Step!
Ah このハードモードな日々
Ah, these hard-mode days,
Days 歩き出すことためらうけど
Days, I hesitate to start walking, but...
BGM決めてさあ 人生エンジョイ勢で
Decide on the BGM and as someone who enjoys life,
のんびりゆこう
let's go leisurely.
先の見えない乱世
In these unpredictable turbulent times,
自分の道通らんせ
go your own way.
オーケー 生きてりゃきっとなんとかなるさ
Okay, as long as you're alive, things will work out.
だいじょぶだいじょぶ
It's okay, it's okay.
後ろ前方向なんてわからない
I don't know back from front,
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
even these days that feel like a labyrinth.
一歩歩き出せたら それが前に
If you can take one step, that becomes...
なるのさ
...'forward'.
万事快調気分な朝でも
Even on mornings when everything feels great,
頭渋滞気味な夜でも
or nights when your head is a bit jammed,
風がいつも吹いてる
the wind is always blowing.
心配しないで
Don't worry,
一緒にファイトでござる！
let's fight together, degozaru!
Ah まだ履き慣れていない
Ah, shoes I'm not used to yet,
シューズ 転びそうになってばかり
I'm always about to fall over.
七転び八起き 何回でもゲームオーバー
Falling seven times and getting up eight, no matter the Game Over,
コンティニューしよう
let's continue.
地獄の沙汰も自分次第
Even the judgment of hell depends on yourself.
たまにミスって非常事態
Sometimes making a mistake is an emergency.
ジーザス 生きてりゃそういう時だってあるさ
Jesus, there are times like that when you're alive.
だいじょぶだいじょぶ
It's okay, it's okay.
1・2・3が聞こえない
I can't hear the 1, 2, 3,
よもや突発的な運命も
even if it's an unexpected fate.
グッドタイミングな予感
A feeling of good timing,
思い立ったが吉日さ
any day you decide is a lucky day.
いつも現実主義なあの人も
Whether it's that person who's always a realist,
かたや妄想癖な誰かも
or someone else with a delusional habit,
夢の中で会えたら 遊び明かしましょう
if we can meet in a dream, let's play all night.
それじゃあねおやすみ
Well then, goodnight.
色は匂へど散りぬるを
Even if colors are fragrant, they fade.
終わりのないはじまりを
To a beginning without end,
歌いながら風のままに
singing, following the wind,
ゆけ！
go!
方向なんて
Direction...
わからない
I don't know.
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even in these labyrinthine days,
一歩歩き出せたら
If I can take one step forward,
それが前になるのさ
That becomes my "forward."
万事快調 気分な朝でも
Even on mornings where everything feels fine,
頭滞気味な夜でも
Or nights when my mind feels stuck,
風がいつ吹いてる
The wind is always blowing.
心配しないで
Don't worry.
自分のペースで
At your own pace,
一緒にファイトで
Let's fight together!
ござる！
Gozaru!
はい。というわけで、
Alright! So,
皆様こんばんはでござる。
good evening everyone.
風真いろは 3周年ミニライブに
Thank you so much for coming to...
お越しいただきまして、ありがとうございます！
...Kazama Iroha's 3rd Anniversary Mini Live!
えー、風真殿、今年は周年3Dライブ
Um, to those of you thinking, "Wait, Kazama-dono,"
なかったんじゃないの？と思っているそこのあなた。
"wasn't there no anniversary 3D live this year?"
実はですね、こちらは今年の誕生日の準備の
Actually, I asked to use the resources prepared
リソースをお願いして使わせていただいて、特別に収録しております。
for this year's birthday to specially record this.
なので、今なんと収録しているのは、
So, I'm actually recording this
風真の誕生日ということで、だいぶ前になるんですけれども、
on my birthday, which was quite a while ago.
未来の隊士さん、そして未来の風真いろは、
Future troopers, and future Kazama Iroha,
見てるー？
are you watching?
という種明かしでございました。
So that was the big reveal.
はい。もしかして「ないから嬉しい」って
I think there might be some troopers
言ってくれてる隊士さんもきっとコメント欄にいるんじゃないかなー、と思うと、
in the comments saying they're happy because they thought there wasn't one.
今ちょっと想像して嬉しい気持ちになっています。
Just imagining that makes me feel happy right now.
今日は3周年の記念配信見てくださり、本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for watching the 3rd anniversary celebratory stream today.
きっとね、今から比べたら
It's November 30th now, right?
11月の30日でしょう？
Compared to then...
今よりも歌絶対上手くなってるし、
I'm sure my singing has improved since then,
今よりも絶対に踊り上手くなっているはずなんですけれども、
and my dancing must have definitely gotten better by now.
今の全力を、精一杯を、
But I've put all my effort into
今回このミニライブに詰めさせていただいております。
this mini live as I am now.
あー、この後見せるのがドキドキするぜ。
Ah, I'm nervous about showing what's next.
そして今回ですね、
And there's another reason
どうしてミニライブをやったかっていうのがもう一つ理由がありまして、
why I'm doing this mini live today.
なんとですね、皆様。
Everyone!
この度、風真いろは、新しいオリ曲を発表させていただくこととなりました！
Kazama Iroha is announcing a new original song!
うわーい！
Yay!
そうなんです。このタイミングで今日新オリジナル曲を公開させていただきます。
That's right. I'm releasing a new original song at this timing.
はい。今回はですね、色々今までオリジナル曲があったと思うんですけれども、
I've had various original songs until now.
「いろはすてっぷ！」は可愛い感じ、
"Iroha Step!" was cute,
あとは「まじかるござる☆」は結構ね、
"Magical Gozaru" was quite...
なんかポップなキャッチーな感じ、
...pop and catchy,
で、「Dreamy Sky」もそんな可愛い感じ、
and "Dreamy Sky" was also cute,
魔法少女の感じですね。
with a magical girl feel.
そして「風を待つ者」みたいな、かっこいい感じでした。
And "Kaze wo Matsu Mono" was a cool song.
結構いろんなオリジナル曲を作ってきたんですけれども、
I've created many different original songs,
今回の曲はなんと、
this time, it's a song that brings
風真いろはの性格的なところを前面に出した曲となっております。
my personality to the forefront.
はい。皆様、3年も風真いろはにお付き合いいただいておりましたら、
If you've been following Kazama Iroha for three years,
風真いろはがとってもちょっと恥ずかしいのが苦手とかね、
many troopers probably know I'm not good
そういった内面があるのはもちろん隊士さんはもうご存知の方も多いかと思うんですけれども、
at handling embarrassment and such.
その内面と、今回は恋愛観をマッチさせた
I've created a love song that matches that side
恋愛ソングを作らせていただきました！
with my views on romance!
恥ずかしくて発作が起きそうです。
I'm so embarrassed I feel like I might have a fit.
けどね、自分のやっぱ内面とか、そういうの表現したい。
But I wanted to express my inner self.
今年は一年、オリジナル曲をいっぱい作りたいということで活動してまいりました。
I've been working to make many original songs this year.
そのために今回もですね、周年で1個公開させていただき、
So for the anniversary, I'm releasing one more
新たな一面を出せればと思っております。
to show a new side of myself.
はい。ちょっと今、発表する前にドキドキしてしょうがないので、この後歌うんですけれども、
I'm so nervous before the announcement, but I'll be singing it now.
そう、このミニライブで初披露になるんですが、
It'll be the first performance at this mini live,
その前に一回お水飲んできますね。
but before that, I'm going to drink some water.
ちょっと、お水飲ませていただきます。お水。お水。
Allow me to drink some water. Water, water...
これお水の踊りね。お水の踊り。
This is the water dance. The water dance.
お水美味しい！
Water is delicious!
すいません。ただいま戻りました。
Sorry. I'm back.
はい。というわけで、改めまして、
Alright. So, once again, this is my new original song
風真いろはのちょっと内面的な性格も含んだ、新オリ曲、そして初めての恋愛ソングとなります。
and first love song, which includes my personality.
ここでミニライブで初披露させていただきます。
I'll be performing it for the first time here at the mini live.
それでは皆様聞いてください。
Please listen, everyone.
堀江晶太さん作曲、
Composed by Shota Horie,
風真いろは新オリジナル曲「ハードモード」。
Kazama Iroha's new original song, "Hard Mode."
ダメだ
It's no use,
果てしない
it's endless.
想定の半分くらい？
Is it about half of what I expected?
もうそれ以上は言えない
I can't say any more,
無理っぽい
it seems impossible.
まだ届いてない？
Has it not reached you yet?
ズキョン 合図を頂戴
Zukyun! Give me a sign.
伝えるまでが
Until I convey it
ミッション
is a mission
賽は投げられた
the die is cast
ハードモード
作詞・作曲・編：ポリスピカデリー
Hard Mode
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Police Piccadilly
皮肉なものね心ボロボロ
It's ironic, my heart is in tatters
息してるだけで褒めてくれよな
Please praise me just for breathing
モヤモヤよこの指とまれ
Vague feelings, stop on this finger
絶対なんて無いね絶対
There's no such thing as "absolute", absolutely
悪魔的予行演習リピート
Devilish rehearsal repeat
大怪我しないためにもね
Just so I don't get seriously hurt
重い想いぶん募ってく
Heavy feelings keep piling up
今はこれが現実
Right now, this is reality
ダメだ 果てしない 想定の半分くらい？
No good, it's endless. About half of what I expected?
もう それ以上は 言えない 無理っぽい
I can't say any more than that, seems impossible
まだ 届いてない？
Hasn't it reached you yet?
ズキュン 合図を頂戴
"Zukyun", give me a sign
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
My mission is until I convey it, the die is cast
伝えるまでがミッション どうにか届いて
My mission is until I convey it, somehow let it reach
どこにもほら潜んでるトラップ
Look, traps are lurking everywhere
詳細は非公開 ご理解ください
Details are private, please understand
君の横顔見つめるだけの専門家かな？
Am I an expert just at gazing at your profile?
お察しください
Please figure it out
新しい季節が来て
A new season arrives
1ミリも進んでないぜ
I haven't moved even 1 millimeter
重い想いぶん沈んでく
Heavy feelings keep sinking
今はそれも真実
Right now, that is also the truth
ダメだ 果てしない 怖いけど知りたい
No good, it's endless. I'm scared but I want to know
それ以上は望んでないよ
I'm not wishing for anything more than that
鼓動がヤバくない？ ゴメン 合図を頂戴
Isn't my heartbeat crazy? Sorry, give me a sign
伝えるまでがミッション ハードモード
My mission is until I convey it, hard mode
構えて！
Get ready!
ダメだ 果てしない 想定の半分くらい？
No good, it's endless. About half of what I expected?
もう それ以上は 言えない 無理っぽい
I can't say any more than that, seems impossible
まだ 届いてない？ ズキュン 合図を頂戴
Hasn't it reached you yet? "Zukyun", give me a sign
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
My mission is until I convey it, the die is cast
伝えるまでがミッション どうにか届いて
My mission is until I convey it, somehow let it reach
待ってて
Wait for me
伝えるまでがミッション 賽は投げられた
My mission is until I convey it, the die is cast
Let's Go！ ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the heart-throbbing blue sky
もっと 風に乗り きらめくの
Ride the wind more and sparkle
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now
Cuteな想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
Cute feelings, look, "bam" over and over again!
瞼にうつる ほうき星
A comet reflected on my eyelids
夜空の中 飛び込んだ Shiny Girl
A Shiny Girl who dove into the night sky
手が届きそうなほど
Almost within reach
近づく三日月 合図して
Signal the approaching crescent moon
街の明かりを数えたら
If I count the city lights
眠りにつく 枕元 Secret Girl
A Secret Girl by the bedside falling asleep
まだ見つからない夢 探しに行こう
Let's go find the dream we haven't found yet
雨の日でも 晴れの日でも
Even on rainy days, even on sunny days
真っ直ぐに咲いてる花のように
Like a flower blooming straight up
いつだってきっと どこだってそっと 輝く魔法
Always surely, everywhere softly, the magic that shines
Let's Go！ ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the heart-throbbing blue sky
もっと 風に乗り きらめくの
Ride the wind more and sparkle
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now
Cuteな想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
Cute feelings, look, "bam" over and over again!
華やかドレス 身に纏い
Wearing a glamorous dress
誰かを待つ 憧れの Princess Girl
The longing Princess Girl waiting for someone
あーなりたい理想と 比べてばっか
Always comparing myself to the ideal I want to be
道に迷って 1人悩んで
Lost on the way, worrying alone
挫けそうになっても 大丈夫！
Even if it feels like I'm going to break, it's okay!
君と出会って 笑顔になって 輝く魔法
Meeting you, becoming a smile, the magic that shines
Let's Go！ ありふれた日常も
Let's Go! Even the ordinary daily life
もっと 風吹いて 動き出す
The wind blows more and starts to move
Jumping 飛び立つ 希望を探して
Jumping, taking off, searching for hope
弾ける想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
Bursting feelings, look, "bam" over and over again!
本当にありがとう
Thank you so much
何度でもパッキュンだ！
Pakkyun over and over!
助けられるだけじゃない わたしも守りたい
Not just being saved, I want to protect too
そう ずっと思い描いた
Yes, the things I've always imagined
日々を繋いで
Connecting the days
重なる いろは
Overlapping Iroha
みんながいたからここまでこれた
I was able to come this far because everyone was here
やっと気づいた 本当の願い
I finally realized my true wish
なんて ちょっぴり大袈裟だけど
It's a bit of an exaggeration, but...
どうか この時間が いつまでも
Please, let this time...
続きますように 君と今
...last forever with you, right now
4年目もみんなと笑っていたいです
I want to keep laughing with everyone in my 4th year too
Let's Go! ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the sparkling blue sky
もっと 風に乗り きらめくの
Riding the wind more, sparkling
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now
Special Thanks かざま隊のみんな
Special Thanks to all the Kazama-tai
Cuteな想い ほら 何度でもパッキュンだ！
Cute feelings, look, "pakkyun" over and over!
これからもよろしくお願いします
Please continue to support me